<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Defs>

	<InterStoryCore.InterPawnDef>
		<defName>InterStory_SamTaylor</defName>
		<label>Sam Taylor</label>
		<faction>OutlanderCivil</faction>
		<pawnImagePath>InterStory/Pawns/Sam</pawnImagePath>
		<introKey>ISST_IntroductionBegin</introKey>
		<helloKey>ISST_HelloBegin</helloKey>
		<rootKeys>
			<li>ISST_GetToKnow_Begin</li>
			<li>ISST_Insult_Begin</li>
			<li>ISST_HelpMilitary</li>
			<li>ISST_HelpFood</li>
			<li>ISST_HelpMedical</li>
			<li>ISST_DEVInfluenceAdd10</li>
			<li>ISST_DEVInfluenceAdd50</li>
			<li>ISST_DEVGoodwillAdd10</li>
			<li>ISST_DEVGoodwillAdd50</li>
		</rootKeys>
		<chatOptions>
			<!-- ============================================================ Hello - Condition Enemies ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_HelloBegin</chatKey>
				<outputText>Howdy there, partner. Our sensors are pickin up a lot of activity over there, I reckon you're calling for some backup? Over.</outputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_UnderAttack</outputWorker>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_HelpMilitaryCheap</li>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>true</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<!-- ============================================================ Introduction Branch ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionBegin</chatKey>
				<outputText>Howdy there, partner. This here's Captain Sam Taylor, space cowboy extraordinaire, coming at ya from the edge of the galaxy. I reckon we got ourselves a new neighbor on this rimworld of ours. Pleasure to make your acquaintance. What can I do ya for, settler? Over.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseA</li>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseSkip</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseA</chatKey>
				<inputText>Hi, nice to meet you! Got any tips for someone just getting started?</inputText>
				<outputText>Well, ain't that a fine question to start with. Surviving on the rimworld can be as wild as a bucking bronco, but fear not, I've got a few nuggets of wisdom to share...</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseB</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseB</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>1. Secure Your Basics: First things first, make sure you've got a solid source of food, fresh water, and shelter. It might sound simple, but out here, it's the foundation of everything.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseC</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseC</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>2. Know Your Surroundings: Scout the area, partner. Look for resources like fertile soil, nearby wildlife, and mineral deposits. Keep an eye out for potential threats too, be it aggressive critters or less friendly neighbors.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseD</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseD</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>3. Build a Strong Team: You can't run a successful colony all on your lonesome. Recruit capable folks with diverse skills - farmers, builders, doctors, you name it. Teamwork makes the dream work, after all.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseE</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseE</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>4. Prepare for Anything: Out here, you gotta be ready for whatever the cosmos throws your way. That means having some defenses in place, be it walls, turrets, or sharpshootin' colonists.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseF</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseF</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>5. Research and Innovate: Invest in research to unlock new technologies. Better gear, advanced medicine, and renewable energy sources can make a heap of difference in the long run.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseG</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseG</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>6. Stay Flexible: The frontier's a changin' place, partner. Adaptability is key. Be ready to switch up your plans if the situation demands it.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseH</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseH</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>7. Trade Smart: Don't hoard your goods like a dragon with its gold. Trade with passing ships and other colonies. You might just find that one thing you need to keep your people smilin'.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_IntroductionResponseI</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
				<allowCloseChat>false</allowCloseChat>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseI</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>Remember, friend, every setback's just a setup for a comeback. If things get tough, don't lose that pioneer spirit. Feel free to holler if you need more advice. Wishing you clear skies and steady hands out there. Over and out.</outputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_IntroComplete</outputWorker>
				<influenceCost>-10</influenceCost>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_NullResponse</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_IntroductionResponseSkip</chatKey>
				<buttonText>Thanks for the welcome, Sam! I think I've got a handle on things...</buttonText>
				<inputText>Thanks for the welcome, Sam! I think I've got a handle on things, I'll give you a call if I need any help!</inputText>
				<outputText>Remember, friend, every setback's just a setup for a comeback. If things get tough, don't lose that pioneer spirit. Feel free to holler if you need advice. Wishing you clear skies and steady hands out there. Over and out.</outputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_IntroComplete</outputWorker>
				<influenceCost>-5</influenceCost>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_NullResponse</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<!-- ============================================================ Personal Information ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_Begin</chatKey>
				<inputText>I'd like to get to know you more.</inputText>
				<outputText>Well, partner, I appreciate your curiosity, I'm an open book, ask away!</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More</li>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More</chatKey>
				<inputText>What do you like to do around here?</inputText>
				<outputText>Well, when I'm not keeping this colony in one piece, you'll find me stargazing, tinkering with tech, playing my guitar, and exploring the wild unknown on my trusty rover. Life's tough, but it's got its moments of beauty and adventure out here on the rim.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More</li>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More</chatKey>
				<inputText>Where did you come from?</inputText>
				<outputText>Boy howdy, settle in 'cause I've got a tale that'd curl your toes.\n\nYears ago, back when I was flyin' the stars in my trusty old ship, the Stardust Serenade, I was a scout for a mining expedition in the outer reaches of the known galaxy. We were chasin' whispers of riches, seekin' out precious resources on uncharted planets.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More_1A</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More</chatKey>
				<inputText>If you had the chance, would you want to leave?</inputText>
				<outputText>Well, I've pondered that question under the starlit sky many a night. As much as I miss the vastness of space and the unknown horizons of the galaxy, this rimworld has become my home. It's where I've forged bonds, faced challenges, and discovered a strength I never knew I had.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More_2A</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<!-- ============================================================ Personal Information - 1 ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More_1A</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>One fateful day, our sensors picked up a blip on the cosmic radar, a signal hintin' at untold wealth. Eager as a coyote on a rabbit's trail, we set our course for that distant star, hopin' to strike it rich. But fate's a tricky mistress, my friend. As we approached the rim of a black hole, somethin' went haywire in our navigational systems. The ship started buckin' like a wild stallion, and before we knew it, we were spiralin' down toward this here rimworld.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More_1B</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More_1B</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>The crash was a roar of thunder and a blaze of fire. The Stardust Serenade, my home among the stars, was reduced to scrap metal in the blink of an eye. Miraculously, I survived, though not without my fair share of bumps and bruises. I found myself stranded on this untamed rock, light-years away from the life I'd known.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More_1C</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More_1C</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>But you know, life's about adaptin'. So, I salvaged what I could from the wreckage, gathered a ragtag group of survivors from the crash, and we started buildin'. We made this rimworld our home, fightin' off the dangers of the frontier together. Now, I'm the captain of the Last Chance Colony, and I've embraced my fate as a space cowboy, ridin' the cosmic trails of the unknown.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More_1D</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More_1D</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>And that, my friend, is how ol' Sam Taylor ended up talkin' to you through this cracklin' communicator on the edge of the galaxy. Life might've thrown me a curveball, but I reckon I've found my own kind of paradise right here on this rimworld.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More</li>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<!-- ============================================================ Personal Information - 2 ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More_2A</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>Leavin' this place would mean leavin' behind the people who've stood by me through thick and thin. It would mean sayin' goodbye to the very essence of what makes this place special - the resilience of the human spirit against the backdrop of the great unknown.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More_2B</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_GetToKnow_More_2B</chatKey>
				<inputText>...</inputText>
				<outputText>So, while the stars might call to me, and the sky above still holds a sense of wonder, I reckon I'll stay right here. There's a whole universe in the hearts of the folks I've come to call family. And in this corner of the cosmos, I've found somethin' precious, somethin' worth fightin' for.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_GetToKnow_More</li>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<!-- ============================================================ Insults ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_Insult_Begin</chatKey>
				<inputText>[Insult...]</inputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_Insult_More</li>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_Insult_More</chatKey>
				<inputText>Your kind is considered a delicacy where I come from!</inputText>
				<outputText>Well, I hope your taste buds enjoy something a bit more exotic than a space cowboy! Around here, we're more inclined to rustle up some local critters for supper. But hey, to each their own in this vast universe. If you ever find yourself on this rimworld, maybe I'll surprise you with a dish that'll change your mind about us space-folk being delicacies!</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_Insult_More</chatKey>
				<inputText>Your mother was a hamster, and your father smelled of elderberries!</inputText>
				<outputText>Well now, that's a line straight out of a classic tale! Reminds me of the kind of banter we'd share around the campfire. You got a knack for humor, friend. If you ever find your way to this rimworld, I reckon we'd get along just fine.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_Insult_More</chatKey>
				<inputText>Yesterday I scrunched a bug with my foot. The spot on the floor had some stunning similarities to your face.</inputText>
				<outputText>Well, I reckon I've had my fair share of scrapes and bruises, but comparin' my face to a bug squish? That's a new one. Guess we all find inspiration in unexpected places, don't we? Just be sure to watch your step - wouldn't want you mistakin' me for a critter out here on the rimworld, partner!</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_Insult_More</chatKey>
				<inputText>Your body is as ineffective as... nope, there is nothing comparable to your body's ineffectiveness.</inputText>
				<outputText>Well, I might not be the most advanced model of spacefaring efficiency, but out here on the rimworld, a little bit of grit and determination goes a long way. We might not have the shiniest gadgets, but we've got heart and tenacity. And sometimes, that's all you need to survive in the vast expanse of the cosmos, my friend.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_Insult_More</chatKey>
				<inputText>May whatever god you believe have mercy on you, we will have none!</inputText>
				<outputText>Well, partner, I reckon I'll take my chances with the cosmic winds and the wild frontier. Out here, mercy can be as rare as a rainstorm in the desert. But who knows, maybe we'll find a little kindness in the stars someday. Until then, we'll keep ridin' these cosmic trails, come what may. Safe travels to you, wherever your journey leads.</outputText>
				<acceptedKeys>
					<li>ISST_ReturnToRoot</li>
				</acceptedKeys>
			</li>
			<!-- ============================================================ Standard Help Requests ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_HelpMilitaryCheap</chatKey>
				<buttonLabel>Cost: 25 Influence</buttonLabel>
				<buttonText>[Request Military Aid]</buttonText>
				<inputText>Yes, please! I was just about to ask!</inputText>
				<outputText>Hold on tight, partner! Captain Taylor's on the way. We ain't lettin' no varmints mess with our neighbors. Buckle up, we're saddlin' up the posse and ridin' to your aid. Stay strong, help's a-comin'! Over and out.</outputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_SendAid</outputWorker>
				<influenceCost>25</influenceCost>
				<needsFaction>true</needsFaction>
				<minGoodwill>0</minGoodwill>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_HelpMilitary</chatKey>
				<buttonLabel>Cost: 30 Influence</buttonLabel>
				<buttonText>[Request Military Aid]</buttonText>
				<inputText>We're under attack from some raiders, could you send some help over?</inputText>
				<outputText>Hold on tight, partner! Captain Taylor's on the way. We ain't lettin' no varmints mess with our neighbors. Buckle up, we're saddlin' up the posse and ridin' to your aid. Stay strong, help's a-comin'! Over and out.</outputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_SendAid</outputWorker>
				<influenceCost>30</influenceCost>
				<needsFaction>true</needsFaction>
				<minGoodwill>20</minGoodwill>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_HelpFood</chatKey>
				<buttonLabel>Cost: 20 Influence</buttonLabel>
				<buttonText>[Request Food Aid]</buttonText>
				<inputText>We could really use some food, if you have any to spare?</inputText>
				<outputText>Hold on tight, partner! Captain Taylor's on the way. We ain't lettin' no varmints mess with our neighbors. Buckle up, we're saddlin' up the posse and ridin' to your aid. Stay strong, help's a-comin'! Over and out.</outputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_SendAid</outputWorker>
				<influenceCost>20</influenceCost>
				<needsFaction>true</needsFaction>
				<minGoodwill>20</minGoodwill>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_HelpMedical</chatKey>
				<buttonLabel>Cost: 20 Influence</buttonLabel>
				<buttonText>[Request Medical Aid]</buttonText>
				<inputText>We could really use some medicine, if you have any to spare?</inputText>
				<outputText>Hold on tight, partner! Captain Taylor's on the way. We ain't lettin' no varmints mess with our neighbors. Buckle up, we're saddlin' up the posse and ridin' to your aid. Stay strong, help's a-comin'! Over and out.</outputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_SendAid</outputWorker>
				<influenceCost>20</influenceCost>
				<needsFaction>true</needsFaction>
				<minGoodwill>20</minGoodwill>
			</li>
			<!-- ============================================================ Return to Root ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_ReturnToRoot</chatKey>
				<inputText>I'd like to talk about something else.</inputText>
				<returnToRoot>true</returnToRoot>
			</li>
			<!-- ============================================================ Developer Tools / Tests / Cheats ============================================================ -->
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_DEVInfluenceAdd10</chatKey>
				<inputText>[DEV: Add Influence - 10]</inputText>
				<influenceCost>-10</influenceCost>
				<devOnly>true</devOnly>
				<returnToRoot>true</returnToRoot>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_DEVInfluenceAdd50</chatKey>
				<inputText>[DEV: Add Influence - 50]</inputText>
				<influenceCost>-50</influenceCost>
				<devOnly>true</devOnly>
				<returnToRoot>true</returnToRoot>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_DEVGoodwillAdd10</chatKey>
				<inputText>[DEV: Add Goodwill - 10]</inputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_RelationsChange</outputWorker>
				<goodwillChange>10</goodwillChange>
				<devOnly>true</devOnly>
				<returnToRoot>true</returnToRoot>
			</li>
			<li>
				<chatKey>ISST_DEVGoodwillAdd50</chatKey>
				<inputText>[DEV: Add Goodwill - 50]</inputText>
				<outputWorker>InterStoryCore.ChatOptionWorker_RelationsChange</outputWorker>
				<goodwillChange>50</goodwillChange>
				<devOnly>true</devOnly>
				<onlyOnce>true</onlyOnce>
				<returnToRoot>true</returnToRoot>
			</li>
		</chatOptions>
	</InterStoryCore.InterPawnDef>

</Defs>